# **Currículum Vitae**

# María Romina Rotela Ibarra

Frontend Web Developer | Software Developer

- Asunción, Paraguay | romyrotela22@gmail.com | +595 972 716 596
- GitHub: github.com/rominarotela | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/romina-rotela-b0a605150/

## **Professional Profile**

I am a 33-year-old professional with over 7 years of experience in general software and web development. I specialize in Frontend technologies (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React) and Backend with Django and PostgreSQL. I have experience in API integration, testing, and application maintenance, as well as in educational projects with high social impact, including educational game development. I am motivated by technological innovation, creative projects, and teamwork, contributing scalable and secure solutions.

# Work Experience

2021 - Present	Web Developer -	Daraguay	Educa	/ Portal META
ZUZT - Present	web Developer -	· Paraguay	<b>Luuca</b>	/ Portal META

- Development of educational web applications using Python, Django, Wagtail, and Moodle.
- API integration and deployment of scalable systems on PostgreSQL
- Use of agile methodologies (Scrum, Taiga) and version control with GitLab.
- UI design with Figma.
- Development and implementation of educational games, Al tools, and web solutions.

#### 2019 - 2021 Web Developer - Definetec

- ERP Odoo and digital billing development.
- Frontend and Backend development with Python, Django, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS.
- Use of Git, GitHub, and Bitbucket.

#### 2017 - 2019 Technical / Administrative Assistant – Mando Paraguay

- Installation and maintenance of equipment.
- Administrative management and customer support.

# 2010 - 2017 Technical Support and Administrative Assistant (AECID, CNLtrading, Mando)

- Preventive hardware and software maintenance.
- Customer service and incident management.

## **Education**

- Primary and Secondary Studies Colegio Villa San Francisco de Asís
- Computer Engineering Universidad Nacional de Asunción / Facultad Politécnica (Thesis in progress).

## **Technical Skills**

- Languages: Python, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, SQL.
- Frameworks: Django, Wagtail, React, jQuery.
- Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL.
- Tools: Git, GitLab, GitHub, Figma, Docker.
- Methodologies: Scrum, Agile.
- Others: IT security, API integration, testing, and deployment.

### Languages

Spanish: Native | Guarani: Basic | English: Intermediate Technical | Portuguese: Basic | French: Basic

# **Courses and Specializations**

■ Computer Science – Colegio Villa San Francisco: Image Editors (Adobe Photoshop) - Vector Graphics (Corel Draw) - Video Editors (Adobe Premiere Pro)

- Computer Technician Professional Specialization and University Extension Center (CEPEU)
- NDG Linux Unhatched Online course offered by Network Development Group
- CCNA Cisco Certified Network Associate CCNA I Introduction to Networks
- React and React Native CLI (currently studying) Online
- Generative Adversarial Networks and Stable Diffusion (currently studying) Online

## **Certificates Obtained**

- "Human Relations and NLP as a Factor of Business Success" Consulting Group
- "Effective Teamwork in Organizations" Consulting Group
- "Developers and Users Meeting" ABC Color
- "Introduction to Data Mining" UNA, San Lorenzo
- "International Cybersecurity Seminar" KavaCon
- "TRIBU Pre-incubation Program" E-VAL Entrepreneurship
- "Conferences on Computational Thinking, Digital Citizenship, and Socio-emotional Skills Meta Innova: First International Seminar on Educational Innovation in Paraguay"
- "Design and Visual Creation Contest Ñamombe'u" First Place

## **Professional References**

- Ing. Martín Poletti (Technology Area Coordinator META): +595 981 241 144
- Lic. Sofía Ríos (Technical Support and Education Specialist ):+595 985 457 857
- Ing. Rodney Rojas (Web Developer META): +595 986 660 738

## **Personal References**

- Ing. Adrián Vera ( Husband ): +595 971 504 107
- Q.F. María Victoria de Rotela (Mother): +595 986 725 783
- Elena Ibarra Mendoza ( Aunt ): +595 21 295 556